Jester Hairston Collection MS040
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Sound recordings unrelated to Jester Hairston, 1910 -- 1989; 1920 -- 1950; MS040.002; 25.2 Linear Feet; 1 Digital Object(s)
  - 'Way back home / The Iowa indian song, 1949; MS040.002.034.00005; Crosby, Bing; Fred Waring and his Pennsylvanians (Box 34)
    New York./ Decca./ 1 sound disc: 78rpm, 10-inch./ Library of Congress Shelf no. Decca 24800 (78A)./ Record from album: Untitled record album 003, MS040.002.026.00008./
  - White Christmas / God rest ye merry gentlemen [sides 3 and 4 of 8], 1942; MS040.002.034.00006; Crosby, Bing (Box 34)
    New York./ Decca./ 1 sound disc: 78rpm, 10-inch./ Library of Congress Shelf no. Decca 23778 (78A)./ Record from album: Untitled record album 002, MS040.002.026.00007./
  - Who's on first? [parts A and B], 1940; MS040.002.034.00007; Abbott & Costello (Box 34)
    Hollywood, CA./ Enterprise./ 1 sound disc: 78rpm, 10-inch./ Library of Congress Shelf no. Enterprise 501 (78A)./ This record is damaged and accessing any of the sound data may be difficult./
  - The bells [sides 1 and 8], 1944; MS040.002.035.00001; Rachmaninoff, Sergei; Santa Monica Symphony Orchestra (Box 35)
    New York./ Asch Recordings./ 1 sound disc: 12-inch./ Asch Shelf no. 4115./
  - The bells [sides 2 and 7], 1944; MS040.002.035.00002; Rachmaninoff, Sergei; Santa Monica Symphony Orchestra (Box 35)
    New York./ Asch Recordings./ 1 sound disc: 12-inch./ Asch Shelf no. 4116./
  - O beautiful city of God / Saved by grace, 1910; MS040.002.035.00003; Smith, Gypsy [Gipsy Smith] (Box 35)
    [United States]./ Columbia./ 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, 12-inch./ Library of Congress Shelf no. Columbia A 5147 (78A)./ Record from album: Untitled record album 010, MS040.002.035.00008./
  - Oh dry those tears, 1910; MS040.002.035.00004; Williams, Evan (Box 35)
    Camden, NJ./ Victor./ 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, 12-inch./ Library of Congress Shelf no. Victor 74199 (78A)./ This record is damaged and accessing any of the sound data may be difficult./ Record from album: Untitled record album 010, MS040.002.035.00008./
  - Open the gates of the temple, 1910; MS040.002.035.00005; Williams, Evan (Box 35)
    Camden, NJ./ Victor./ 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, 12-inch./ Library of Congress Shelf no. Victor 74198 (78A)./ Record from album: Untitled record album 010, MS040.002.035.00008./
  - Somebody knows / Who could it be?, 1921; MS040.002.035.00006; Smith, Gypsy [Gipsy Smith] (Box 35)
    [United States]./ Columbia./ 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, 12-inch./ Columbia Shelf no. A6204./ Record from album: Untitled record album 010, MS040.002.035.00008./
  - Tchaikowsky 1st symphony, 1945; MS040.002.035.00007; Santa Monica Symphony Orchestra; Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilyich (Box 35)
    New York./ Asch Recordings./ 1 sound disc: 12-inch./ Asch Shelf no. 4105./
  - Untitled record album 010, 1945 -- 1965; MS040.002.035.00008; Unknown (Box 35)
    This album originally contained the following records: MS040.002.035.00003 MS040.002.035.00004 MS040.002.035.00005 MS040.002.035.00006
  - Foreign language records unrelated to Jester Hairston (12"), MS040.002.038 (Box 38)
  - Foreign language records unrelated to Jester Hairston (10"), MS040.002.039 (Box 39)
- Jester Hairston subject files and musical scores, 1928 -- 1998; 1960 -- 1970; MS040.003; 1.45 Linear Feet
  This series contains Hairston's personal file and a copy of his file from the Office of Estate and Gifts Planning microfiche collection (UA040), which contains biographical material, interviews, correspondence, clippings, press releases, speeches, and student records from the 1920s through the 1990s. This series also contains subject files and musical scores by other composers. These files include ASCAP (American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers) material, musical scores by Lorraine and Gale Enger, the score for a "Musical Introduction of Jester Hairston," material about Hairston's collaborator Salli Terri, and photographs of Hairston and Terri.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - ASCAP (American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers) material sent to Jester Hairston, 1963; MS040.003.036.00001 (Box 36)
  - Hairston, Jester A1929 H1972, 1928 -- 1998; MS040.003.036.00002 (Box 36)
    This file includes clippings, press releases, speeches, and student records related to Jester Hairston.
  - Musical Introduction of Jester Hairston, 1979; MS040.003.036.00003; Hairston, Jackie (Box MS040 Shared 1)
    These three sheets of handwritten music are located with the record 'Symphonic Spirituals,' where they were originally found. The song was written by Jester Hairston's cousin, Jackie Hairston.
  - Musical scores by Lorraine and Gale Enger, 1967; MS040.003.036.00004; Enger, Lorraine and Gale (Box 36)
    File contains musical scores (lyrics by Lorrain Enger and music by Gale Enger): "This I Know," "Something Happened," "Look Up," "Look at You," "There is a Way," "What is it About You," "Something Good's about to Happen," "Take a Look All Around," "The Good Things," "It's All So Very Diff'rent Now," "Our Love," "Just Once, and " I Can't Believe (Our Love is Through)."
  - Office of Estate and Gifts file - Brochures, photographs, and copies of original folders, 1942 -- 1978; MS040.003.036.00005; Unknown (Box 36)
    File contains material printed from Hairston's file in UA040: Office of Estate and Gifts Planning microfiche collection.
  - Office of Estate and Gifts file - California Congressional Tribute to Hairston, 1964; MS040.003.036.00006; Unknown (Box 36)
  - Office of Estate and Gifts file - Hairston clippings, 1949 -- 1986; MS040.003.036.00007; Unknown (Box 36)
  - Office of Estate and Gifts file - Hairston correspondence, 1932 -- 1982; MS040.003.036.00008; Unknown (Box 36)
  - Office of Estate and Gifts file - Hairston donation and gifts information, 1951 -- 1981; MS040.003.036.00009; Unknown (Box 36)
  - Office of Estate and Gifts file - Hairston resumes and biographies, 1948 -- 1972; MS040.003.036.00010; Unknown (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Jester Hairston and Salli Terri, 1964; MS040.003.036.00011 (Box 36)
    Photographs of Jester Hairston and Salli Terri, a singer with whom he frequently collaborated. One of the photographs is inscribed from Salli Terri to Hairston.
  - Publicity material about Salli Terri, 1964; MS040.003.036.00012 (Box 36)
    This file contains publicity material about Salli Terri that was sent to Jester Hairston.